RG 004:098, Norfolk Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Norfolk Probate Court records
1778-1971
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Norfolk District)
26 cubic feet
Record books, 1778-1923; Probate files, 1779-1971.
RG004_098
1919-036, 2011-038, 2013-011
The Norfolk Probate District was constituted May 1779, from the Litchfield and Simsbury Probate Districts. The Norfolk Probate District merged with the Canaan, Cornwall, Salisbury, and Sharon Probate Districts on January 1, 2007 to create the Northwest Corner Probate District. The Northwest Corner Probate District merged with the Harwinton, Litchfield, and Thomaston Probate Districts on January 5, 2011, to create the Litchfield Hills Probate District. The Litchfield Hills Probate District serves the municipalities of Canaan, Cornwall, Harwinton, Kent, Litchfield, Morris, Norfolk, North Canaan, Salisbury, Sharon, Thomaston, and Warren.
The Norfolk Probate District also included the municipalities of Colebrook from May 1779 to April 30, 1838 and Winchester from May 1779 to May 30, 1838.
Town of Norfolk, Probate District chronology:
October 1758 - May 1779, Litchfield District
May 1779 - December 31, 2006, Norfolk District
January 1, 2007 - January 4, 2011, Northwest Corner District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Litchfield Hills District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, 1778-1978. Contact the probate court to access record books after Volume 16. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1779-1971. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1779-1900 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered 1-16. There os also a volume of wills numbered 1 and volumes of commitments and bonds, both unnumbered.
Probate files in accessions 1919-036 and 2013-011 are arranged alphabetically.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1919-036 are represented in this index.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the files in accession 2013-011.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Colebrook; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Norfolk; Probate records -- Connecticut -- Winchester
Places:
Colebrook (Conn.); Norfolk (Conn.); Winchester (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2011-038, Record books, 1778-1978 are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-6, 8, 10-11,13-15, 1778-1917; probate files, 1779-1880; and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1919-036 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): September 25, 1919 (1779-1900); September 23, 1930 (1810-1896).
The probate files in accession 2013-011 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on September 24, 2012.
The record books in accession 2011-038 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on October 28, 2010.
Container List
- Record books, 1778-1978; 9 cubic feet (19 volumes); 2011-038
  - Records, 1778-1817 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1810-1826 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1825-1836 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1832-1845 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1846-1856 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1855-1869 (Volume 6)
  - Orders and decrees, 1859-1887 (Volume 7)
    On spine: "Records"
  - Records, 1878-1890 (Volume 8)
  - Orders and decrees, 1886-1902 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1889-1896 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1896-1902 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1902-1907 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1902-1906 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1906-1912 (Volume 14)
  - Records, 1913-1917 (Volume 15)
  - Records, 1917-1923 (Volume 16)
  - Wills, 1857-1863 (Volume 1)
  - Bonds, 1886-1936 (Volume unnumbered)
  - Commitments, 1903-1978 (Volume unnumbered)
- Probate files, 1779-1900; 4 cubic feet; 1919-036
  - Adams - Camp, B. (Drawer 1)
  - Camp, C. - Humphrey, J. (Drawer 2)
  - Humphrey, K. - Richards (Drawer 3)
  - Rider - Wilson (Drawer 4)
  - Wolcott - Z; Miscellaneous (Drawer 5)
- Inventory Control Book, 1779-1900; T003073
  Index of the four accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1919-036
  Date span is coverage
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Probate files, 1779-1971; 13 cubic feet; 2013-011
  The dates for Boxes 1-11 are 1827-1839, 1899-1971
  - Allen - Carter (Box 1)
  - Carbally - Cutter (Box 2)
  - Daepp - Frothingham (Box 3)
  - Gardiner - Hotchkiss (Box 4)
  - Howard - Kunhardt (Box 5)
  - Lagier - McClellan (Box 6)
  - Mead - Ostrander (Box 7)
  - Paine - Ryan (Box 8)
  - Schenherr - Street (Box 9)
  - Sieler - Voight (Box 10)
  - Walcott - Zecher (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous, Abro - Hungerford, 1833-1855, 1882-1913 (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous, B-H, Ives-Yale, 1779-1865, 1899-1910 (Box 13)